Register of the William Jefferson Marshall Papers, 1942-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
William Jefferson Marshall Papers,
1942-1975
81061
Marshall, William Jefferson, 1903-
2 manuscript boxes, 6 envelopes, 1 oversize folder (1.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diaries, orders, reports, correspondence, clippings, certificates, maps, cartoons, and photographs, relating mainly to U.S. naval operations in the Atlantic and Pacific Theaters during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United States. Navy--Officers.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations.; United States--Armed Forces.
Biographical Note
1903, February 5 Born, Henderson, Kentucky
1925 B.S., United States Naval Academy
1933 M.S., University of California, Berkeley
1939-1941 Commanding Officer, U.S.S. Goff
1942 Commanding Officer, U.S.S. Winslow
1942-1943 Commander, United States Navy, Flag Secretary, Staff Commander, Destroyers Atlantic Fleet
1943-1944 Commander, Destroyer Division Thirty-Six Atlantic Fleet, commanded destroyers during Normandy Invasion
1944-1945 Captain, United States Navy, Commander, Destroyer Squadron Forty-Eight Pacific Fleet, commanded destroyers during Philippine Invasion and Okinawa Invasion
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, ca. 1955-1975
  - Biography of Marshall by the Distilled Spirits Council of the United States of America, Inc., 1975 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, ca. 1955 (Folder 2)
  - Resume, ca. 1960 (Folder 3)
- DIARIES, 1942-1945
  - War diaries, including action reports, reports of operations, and other related naval correspondence, 1942 May 23-1945 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1942-1959
  - Eller, E. M., Admiral, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ferrari-Aggradi, Filippo, 1959 (Folder 6)
  - Flanary, Mildred K., 1955 (Folder 7)
  - Marshall, Nancy (wife), 1942-1945 (Folder 8)
  - United States. Navy Department. Bureau of Personnel, 1945-1955 (Folder 9)
- OFFICE FILE, 1953-1956
  - Naval Operations, Navy Department - Assignments for additional duty, naval memoranda, etc., 1953 April 13-1956 January 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- SUBJECT FILE, ca. 1815-1960
  - "Battle Experience: Supporting Operations for the Invasion of Northern France," 1944 June (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hatch, Alden, General Ike, ca. 1944 (excerpt) (Folder 12)
  - McCandless, Bruce - Request for resurrection, 1954 March 25 (Folder 13)
  - Military economic intelligence
    - Eisenberg, Robert, "Economic Contributions from Occupied Areas: German Experiences," n.d. (Folder 14)
    - German economic intelligence (Folder 15)
    - Keller, Joseph W., "The Changing Nature and Need of Economic Intelligence," 1944 July 14 (Folder 16)
    - Kirsch, D. G., "The Field of Activity of the War Economy Staff: Foreign Division," 1943 July 1 (Folder 17)
  - National Security Act, 1947 (Folder 18)
  - Rose, Robert M., "Documents Addressed to Robert M. Rose and Others, 1815-1823" (Folder 19)
- MISCELLANEOUS, ca. 1942-1955
  - Citations, awards, certificates, etc. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Navy cartoons
  - Navy war maps, 1937-1945 (Box Map case)
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - See photo card file (Photo-file Photo file)